Joseph Greaney

Mobile: +447930 348605 Email: joegreaney98@yahoo.com

Website: joe-v2.github.io

Profile

A forward-thinking C# and Python developer, with an appetite for progression and great ambition. Established organisational and professional skills as a team leader, with a reputation for trust and openness. Strong team ethos and analytical ability, with a love for challenging work. Developed & proven communication and interpersonal skills. Keen interest in virtual and augmented reality applications, visual rendering, remote operations and researching new things.

Technical Skills

C# and Python
Git Subversion Management
Procedural Mesh Generation
UX and UI Design
Agile and Scrum Framework Integration
Continuous Integration and Deployment Management

Unity Engine and Editor Scripting Software Diagnostics and Prognosis AWS, Sentry and API Integration Jenkins Pipeline Monitoring Jira, Bitbucket and Confluence Blender, Photoshop and Procreate

Relevant Experience

3D Developer / Kanban Team Leader: Planner Development, Wren Kitchens April 2022 – Present

Managing deployments, and continuous integration of developed items of value, into a multi-platform codebase via Jira and Jenkins pipelines. Improving user experiences on an international scale, as software builds and ships to showrooms throughout the UK and USA. Building scalable features across technical and creative disciplines, using C# with Unity scripting and asset bundle management. Assisting Quality Assurance and internal developers with tools for improved insight into ongoing issues, and facilitating improved communications between support and end users. Scoped and specified on projects designed to scale with increased international adoption, earning the legal protection of patent applications and accredited inventorship.

Leading a team of two developers and three QA testers, whilst integrating Agile and Scrum principles within a itemised Kanban workflow. Using Jira to monitor team performance, and plan ahead accordingly on a rolling weekly schedule. Scoping multiple internal projects to improve issue diagnostics, whilst pre-emptively intercepting software issues within minutes of event occurrence. Working with product owners and stakeholders to shape internal process and priorities, within consistently realistic timeframes whilst maintaining high standards of quality. Integrating new members of the department into the process, assisting skill growth and domain knowledge transfer within staff, to create production-ready feature developers. Facilitating and fulfilling team member needs via cross-team communications, both within a department and across the company.

Junior 3D Developer: Planner Development, Wren Kitchens

June 2021 - April 2022

Produced continuous, project-focused and business-centric points of value for external product owners. Illustrated visual outcomes of technical solutions via live demonstrations, given within Scrum ceremonies to key stakeholders, using Unity with C#. Worked as part of a five-person development team, synchronising with Git and using Jira for priorotised issue management. Pinpointed errors within root cause hypotheses for customer-journey-centric issues as a matter of routine, and delivered working patches for problems on the same day. Interfaced with artists as an internal provider of development tools, to increase efficiency and maintain heightened synergy between teams. Developed testing routines for internal Quality Assurance, and assisted with improving internal diagnostic practices. Delivered retail-ready features, across Mac, Windows, HTC VR and distributed rendering platforms, as a part of projects with business values in the millions. Continuously improved in professional skills, and never received a progression objective grading below A.

Laboratory Assistant: University of Hull, Faculty of Science & Engineering February 2018 – May 2021

Assisted with preparation and fulfilment of practical lab sessions. Educated second and third year students in a variety of paradigms, including Unity with C# scripting, Hololens 2 and Vive Pro deployment, Javascript and XML integration, and Git repository systems. Guided students through laboratory assignments, helping them build spherical surround video viewing software. Assisted second year students in managing team projects for system specification and functionality implementation, whilst developing contemporary ethical understanding with respect to data handling. Monitored and assessed student progress on behalf of Lecturers, and guided many to success.

Joseph Greaney

Mobile: +447930 348605 Email: joegreaney98@yahoo.com

Website: joe-v2.github.io

Education

BSC Computer Science: First Class with Honours, University of Hull

September 2016 - July 2020

Completed functional software assignments, demonstrating capability towards independent study and understanding new and radical development concepts. Communicated effectively via written reports and group scrum meetings, and adapted to remote working by adopting agile development strategies.

Focused on research and development for head-mounted displays, improving team workflows by leading when necessary, whilst developing room-scale simulations with facilities for remote control. Managed long-term schedules for multiple concurrent deliverables, learning to effectively use iterative development strategies to progress. Used subversion management via Git to maintain changelogs, track task completion and gauge progress throughout.

Modules

Third Year: Virtual Environments, Advanced Software Engineering, Visualization, Data Mining and Decision Systems. Second Year: Electronics and Interfacing, Database Techniques, Systems Analysis Design and Process, Artificial Intelligence, Advanced Programming, Networking and User Interface Design.

Virtual Environments - Managed a group project developing software for the HoloLens platform, using Unity with C# scripting to enable remote operation and calibration. Developed a 360-degree video player for the Oculus Rift, with diegetic user interfaces, and focus-activated displays.

Research Project (Virtual Environments and Dexterity) - Planned and documented a research project for evaluating spatial distortion effects in virtual reality, which incorporated a virtual testing environment to be deployed on the Oculus Rift Touch platform, using Unity with C#. Developed custom assets using 3DS Max and Blender. Successfully implemented environments captured using photogrammetry, automatically generated experimental metrics, hand-dependent controller inputs and remotely configurable avatar user representation.

Visualisation - Used Git source control, D3.JS and Paraview to create and evaluate scalable, multi-dimensional abstract visualisation objects for engineering and financial data sets. Produced interactive radar charts and OHLC stock graphs, for implementation in a front-end oriented web environment.

Advanced Programming - Produced a wordsearch solver using C++, with process threading, pointers, references, linked lists, and efficiency instrumentation.

MSC Computer Science for Games Development, University of Hull

September 2020 – June 2021

Practised efficiency-oriented approaches to produce C++ and DirectX practical assignments, using GitHub for synchronising workflows around online code repositories, allowing for development from home. Repurposed C# software using Monogame libraries as part of an agile development team, using scrum frameworks and online Kanban tools to synchronise across a sprint-centric workflow. Used Git-based branching and pull requests to develop as a team.

Projects and Interests

Creative Asset Design

Produced poster graphic, three-dimensional model and merchandise designs for University societies and student union election campaigns, across Hull and York. Developed virtual environments for the Janus VR platform, using Source 2 and Unity. Used Procreate and Photoshop to produce merchandising designs for an indoor art market.

Music and Audio Production

Experimented with physically-modelled VSTs, sample banks and simulated guitar effects to produce standalone music projects, and score various independent game titles. Released 3 EP collections via online music streaming services, gaining a small international audience.

Game Design

Developed a variety of small, exercise-oriented titles across multiple genres – with one releasing to the google play store. Other titles remain in development, but preview sessions available on request.